Subtitle translation by Winifred Donlon
Modify by Blue-Bird™
It has now been seven months
since Spain
began applying European measures
to tackle the shortage of basic resources.
The plan, called ''Not Enough for All,"
has started to produce results.
But for now, Spain,
as well as its neighboring countries,
won't be able
to sustain dependent citizens until...
Get to your positions.
Come on. Same as last time.
- Let's do this.
- Let's go.
Meet back at the trucks. Be careful, okay?
- Let's go. Quickly and quietly.
- Run fast.
Bring your things. Hurry. Come on.
Come on. Move it. Move it. Go, go, go.
- Come on. Come on, quickly.
- Come on, Mia. Let's go.
- Hurry up. Quickly.
- Where?
This way.
Move it. Move it.
You two, follow me.
This way, guys. Come on!
This way.
Faster.
Faster. Move it.
Come on. Let's go.
- You okay?
- No.
Don't stop. Let's go.
That way.
Let's go. Come on. Move. You first.
Okay.
- Nico.
- I'm here.
- I don't fit. Fuck, I don't fit!
- You can do it.
- Push me.
- Okay.
Sorry.
- Are you okay? Yeah, you're okay.
- What?
Back up!
Let's go.
Come on. Follow me.
Hold my hand.
Come on.
Let's go, love.
Stay back, don't move.
Now!
Through here. Almost there.
Attention! Put your hands in the air!
Stay where you are.
This is the police. You are under arrest.
Give me the money.
You wait here.
- Are you okay?
- Okay.
Didn't tell me about these two.
Bring 'em over.
You, here.
It's fine.
- Is anything wrong?
- The conditions are riskier than expected.
I need more money.
No, no, no. We don't have any more money.
I see how this works.
- Babe, give me your ring.
- No.
- Yes. You've got to.
- No. We gave them everything. Not my ring!
Mia, we've got to leave now.
Take it.
Come on.
Come on. We don't have all night. Move it.
Good. This way.
Safe travels.
We're gonna make it.
There it is. Our luxury liner.
Move it, asshole!
- Come on.
- Let's go!
Now!
Step to the back.
- Are you okay?
- No.
There's no food!
We accepted
the discourse about shortages.
We accepted that we had to make sacrifices
for the common good.
We accepted
that measures would be temporary.
But what now?
Look how far they've pushed us.
First, they exterminated the elderly
to deal with the shortages.
Now they're targeting
pregnant women and kids.
Don't you see it? Pregnant women and kids!
The regime isn't ending shortages.
Is there anything else on?
There are alternatives
to this massacre.
Countries like Ireland,
Iceland, and Norway have managed to stop...
- Yeah, take it off.
- Okay.
Our country
must follow their example and help...
Let me see.
Wow.
That's better.
- Okay? Here.
- Yeah.
Make him shut up.
Where'd you get this?
Ah...
Tell me.
It's a secret.
Let's not have it now.
Let's save it
and eat it when we get there.
- To celebrate, right?
- Exactly.
Do you think the regime will go there too?
Ireland has ruled in opposition to it.
Doesn't matter.
Governments are falling everywhere.
- I'll tell you something about the Irish.
- What?
It's impossible to overthrow them.
- They drink dark beer.
- Right.
Ireland won't give in.
You're allowed to be afraid, you know.
Everything will work out, you'll see. Hmm.
- You don't know for sure.
- The worst part is over.
You don't know that.
There's one thing I do know.
What?
That I love you more than yesterday.
But less than tomorrow.
What's happening? Are we there?
We're leaving.
Turn off the games.
Do you think she's pregnant?
She's all alone.
If she's pregnant, she's not alone.
How's our little Noa doing?
I didn't know we decided yet.
Noa.
- What do you wanna name her?
- I hope it isn't a girl.
I mean it.
Well, I think she's a girl, a warrior.
Just like her mother.
I don't feel her.
What?
She hasn't kicked me in two days.
That's not good.
Why didn't you tell me?
Dunno.
What are you doing?
Haven't you noticed?
She always pushes right here.
I think this is a foot.
How do you do it?
What?
Act like everything's fine.
Like nothing's happened to us.
You know that's not true.
- You know, don't you?
- Mm-hmm.
You brought my duck!
Hi, there. What's wrong?
Tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk.
No, no, no. Don't cry.
- What does the duck say?
- Shh. Don't cry. You're okay.
- Shh.
- Nico.
Yeah?
What if she's alive,
and we're leaving her behind?
All alone.
She's not alive.
They took her away,
and they killed her.
Hmm.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Nico! Nico!
Mia!
Come on, now! Hurry up! Move it!
Move it! Get in there now! Come on!
What are you doin'?
Stop. There's too many. Back out!
- Nico! Nico!
- Mia!
Listen up! There's too many of you.
There's another truck coming.
- Half of you get out. Now!
- You heard him! It's too full.
- Get some of 'em out!
- Come on! Come on! Get outta here!
Mia! Mia! Mia!
- Nico!
- Get out!
- Wait! Mia!
- Come on, keep moving. Hey, you!
You can't stay!
Hey. Are you deaf or what?
Get off the truck.
No, no. I was on this one, with my wife!
- Get out!
- Nico!
- The rest move back.
- Stay back!
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no! Please! No!
No. No, no, no. Nico. No, no, no.
Keep moving! Come on! To the back!
Nico. Nico.
Nico.
Nico. No.
Nico, Nico.
One-zero-seven green.
No. No, please. Wait, wait, wait.
- Mia.
- Babe, are you all right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
- Okay, Nico.
- Yeah?
- How will we find each other again?
- We're okay. My truck is behind yours.
- I can't do this alone.
- What?
No, no.
I can't do it alone, I really can't.
Listen to me. You can't trust anyone.
Understand? Keep your things tucked away.
Be careful, my love.
Yeah.
Did you hear me?
Mia, are you there? Mia!
Nico, listen to me.
Are you sure they're taking us
to the same location?
Yes, and when they stop, I'll escape.
Our ship is the only one
setting sail this week.
- Nico.
- Yes?
I wanna be with you.
Me too. I love you, Mia.
Don't worry,
everything's gonna be all right.
- Okay.
- We're gonna be okay.
- We'll talk soon, all right?
Don't go yet, don't hang up.
Love, we can't waste our batteries.
Please don't hang up yet.
We'll be together again soon, you'll see.
- Nico.
- Yeah?
Come soon.
I will. As soon as I can.
Okay.
What makes you think
you're better than us?
Little girl, be quiet.
GIVE US OUR CHILDREN BACK
No, please, no!
No...
MURDERERS!
THIS IS NOT THE WAY
What's going on?
Hey.
- What's going on?
- Move to the back.
Don't talk.
How you doin'?
Good, thanks.
Step outside.
Bring your documents.
Do I have to get out?
- Transporting?
- Behind schedule.
Very good.
Come with me to the back, please.
Uh, sure.
This is the entire load?
Yes.
You can't tell me what you're moving?
Small load. All in the manifest.
I know what it says.
Problem is you don't.
Look, it's been a long week.
I log a lot of miles.
Lots of shipments.
Stop!
Is there a problem?
Another one's pullin' in.
He can park there.
Am I clear?
You in a rush?
Uh, it's just if... if I'm late,
I'll be penalized.
Well, I'm required
to check inside the truck.
But is that necessary?
I'm barely carrying anything.
Don't worry about it.
I'll write you a note.
Travis, back here.
Do it!
Great, thank you.
Well done.
You can come out now.
Don't be afraid. We won't hurt you.
You won't come out?
I know that the austerity measures
have been cruel.
They're especially hard
on women and children.
I understand
if you don't think you can trust me.
It's hard to know
who to trust, right? Hmm?
Not those who forced you
into this container.
They stuffed you in here
with barely enough air to breathe
and robbed you
of all the money you had left.
And they promised you...
...you could have a better life
in a better place.
They lied.
A better place doesn't exist.
So you should come out.
Because if you don't, I'll have to shoot.
Damn it. Don't make me give that order.
I've had to give it so many times.
I can save your lives.
Well, I tried.
Come. Take my hand.
Hey! Good for you!
Come on up! Take my hand!
All right, boys. You know what to do.
Puppy!
Get the bodies out of here
and get rid of all their shit.
Take this one.
Good enough. Let's go.
- All good, boss.
- Great.
Nico. You've gotta hide. Hide, Nico.
They killed everyone.
You've gotta hide.
They're gonna kill you. Hide, Nico.
Hello, this is Nico.
I can't talk now, but try me again later.
Nico.
I'm okay and I'm at the port.
Where are you?
Where are you? Why don't you pick up?
Just call me.
- Watch out, it's gonna come loose.
- Help!
I need help!
Come on, let's go!
It's gonna fall! Watch out!
Please help!
Hey! Hey! I'm in here!
Let me out! Please, I'm here!
Hey! Hey!
I'm in here!
Help!
- Help!
- It's going to fall!
Please, help me!
- Is somebody there?
- Yes, I'm here! Help me, please!
God.
Help.
What?
No, no, no, no. No.
No way.
Please.
Please. Please.
Aw, come on.
ENTER PIN NUMBER
INCORRECT PIN
PIN BLOCKED
Okay.
Fuck.
Shit.
No, no, no, no. No, no, no.
Oh, no.
What?
Hey!
Nico, I'm over here!
Nico!
Over here!
No, no, no!
Hey!
Nico! Nico!
Nico!
Where are you?
Hang on! Just hang on! Wait.
Okay.
Nico!
Wait, wait, wait, wait! Wait!
Wait. Wait!
Nico!
It's me. Come on, answer the phone.
Please, answer me. No, no, no, no.
No!
No! Please, I'm here!
Hello, this is Nico.
I can't talk now, but try me again later.
Huh.
Huh?
Are you there?
No.
Hello?
Hi.
No! What?
What's happening?
Okay.
Come on.
Come on!
Really? More Tupperware?
Fucking Tupperware! Shit.
Okay.
Brilliant.
DAY 2
MAXIMUM
All right.
Hello?
No signal.
What? Oh!
UNKNOWN NUMBER
- Mia. Mia, sweetheart.
- Nico?
- Yes.
- Oh! Oh!
Oh my God! Thank God!
Nico, I didn't think you were alive.
Love, are you okay?
I'm sorry I couldn't call.
My battery ran out.
The driver fucked us over.
He left us outside the city limits.
It'll take a few days to catch up.
No. Listen to me.
Something's happening to me, Nico.
- What's wrong?
- I'm trapped in here and I can't get out.
I'm coming to you.
I'm coming. I'll be there soon.
No, no, no. You've gotta listen to me.
I'm not... You won't...
What? What's going on?
I'm not on the boat.
- What do you mean?
- I'm not on the boat.
- My container's in the ocean.
- Wait. Your... What? Where are you?
I don't know. I'm floating in the ocean.
I'm drifting. I don't know where.
I'm okay for now,
but the water's seeping in.
Oh my God, Mia.
Can you see anything outside?
Yes, I can see, but all there is is water.
There's just water.
- There's nothing else?
- Nothing. Just water.
- I'm in the middle of the ocean, Nico.
- Fuck!
Say something. I'm scared.
Just don't worry, Mia.
I'll rescue you. I promise.
- Nico...
- Just try to hang in there.
- I'm trying, but I...
- Do it for the baby.
I don't think I can do this much longer.
- You can do it.
- I just miss her so much, Nico.
No, no, no, no. No, no.
- My love, don't do this. Not now.
- I messed up again.
It's not your fault. Do you understand?
What happened to Uma was not your fault.
- Sweetheart.
- It wasn't?
You're the strongest person
I've ever known.
- Promise you won't give up?
- Yes.
- Mia...
- Yeah?
I love you more than yesterday.
But less than tomorrow.
I will call you
as soon as I figure out a plan.
- Find me. Bye.
- Don't lose your phone.
Oh no, no, no, no, no. Not now.
Not now. Don't do this right now.
Just wait. Help Mommy and wait.
Daddy's on his way.
Wait for Daddy to come.
No. No, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Please, please wait. Wait a bit longer.
Please wait, please wait a little longer.
I wanted you to wait!
Nico!
No!
Ah! No, no, no!
What? Come on. Come on, come on, come on.
Breathe, please. Please. Come on.
Come on, breathe. Breathe. Breathe.
Oh please, breathe.
Mm-hmm.
Oh! Oh!
DAY 2
DAY 3
Honey. Sweetie.
What's wrong?
Want a fresh diaper? Yes?
All right, all right.
It's okay. I can hear you.
You're so loud. I know, I know.
You're hungry, aren't you?
Okay, it's coming. That's right. Hang on.
It's coming.
Come on, sweetie. I know you're hungry.
Come on, lovie.
You're hungry, but you won't eat.
It's okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
Everything's all right.
Mommy needs to eat too.
Mm...
No fucking way. Fuck.
Yes, I know, I know, it's okay.
All right. Come on.
Honey, why won't you eat? Okay...
Hey, listen, listen, listen, listen.
Your job is to eat,
and my job is to take care of you, okay?
We're gonna get out of here, promise.
Please don't be so sad, honey.
Hey! That's enough now!
I have to do this so we can get out
of here and get some help. Okay?
Be quiet and let me work!
Try to be patient for me, please.
Okay. I'm coming.
Okay, my love. I'm here.
Honey, it's okay.
Okay. You're starving.
Honey...
Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on. Come on.
Be quiet! Stop! Stop this! Enough!
You have to eat or you will die!
You wanna die?
Huh? Is that what you want?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, baby.
Mommy loves you.
I'm sorry. Forgive me. I didn't mean it.
I'm gonna take care of you.
I know, I know.
I'm so sorry.
It's all right.
Come here, my little warrior.
Let's try again. Okay?
Still hungry?
I know, and we're gonna try again.
You've been waiting for so long.
I'm sorry it took so long.
I know, I know, I know.
Ready?
Here we go, sweetheart.
That's it.
Latch on for Mommy.
Keep drinking for Mommy.
Mommy's milk came.
Finally.
That's right.
Good girl.
We're good, we're good, we're good.
Mm...
Mm.
Come on!
All right. Almost there.
Huh? What's going on?
No. Come on!
Please work.
Let's go.
Come on!
No.
No!
No...
Yes!
Come on.
No. No.
Please work. Come on, work!
Come back! Please!
Don't do this to me!
Ugh! Come on! No! No. no. no. Hey!
Ugh.
No!
It's all right.
It's all right, sweetie. I know.
That's better, isn't it?
Shh, there, that's better.
Much, much better.
Mm...
Hm...
Eh...
I'm here. I'm here. I'm here.
Don't cry. It's okay.
I'm here, sweetie. Mommy's here.
Don't worry. I'm here.
Don't be afraid. It's okay, it's okay.
Okay.
Go away!
Get outta here!
Okay. It's gone.
I've got you. I'm here.
It's gone.
DAY 6
Huh?
Mm.
- Mommy?
- Uma, my darling.
Uma, please come here.
Come closer. Please. I wanna see you.
Hi, honey.
Mommy, can we go home now, please?
I miss you so much, Uma.
Mommy, why did you let them take me away?
I'm sorry.
It was my fault.
I just wanted to play with the airplane.
I know, it was a mistake.
No, stay.
I'm sorry.
It was my fault. I messed up.
It wasn't your fault.
Mommy will
get you out of here, okay?
Sweetheart. Look at the world.
Up above is the sky.
Down below is the sea.
And very far over there
is where we're going.
Nico, where are you?
Feels good to be outside, right?
Yeah, you seem much happier.
You like the sun and fresh air.
This way. Over here.
Here.
Come on. Over here. This way.
Here. I'm here.
Shh! It's okay, my love.
I'm here. It's okay. It's okay.
I'm here. I'm here.
Oh my God. Oh my God. Oh my God.
I've got this.
Oh.
Don't worry, sweetie.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
Come on, come on. Come, come, come, come.
Come on.
Don't give me that look. I'm desperate.
You know what it feels like.
MAXIMUM
DAY 9
Good job. You're Mommy's big girl.
It's mini bath time.
Where are you? Where are you?
Call me. Come on, Nico. Call me.
Call me, please. Call me!
DAY 12
Look, this is me.
At school.
With one of my students.
Did I tell you I'm a teacher?
This is your daddy. His name's Nico.
He's at work, in our store.
We were forced to close the store
because there wasn't much food to sell.
At the end, there wasn't anything at all.
But people came to visit him anyway.
Because he cared about them.
I know he'll find a way
to get us out of here
because... he always knows what to do.
This is your grandma, Noa.
Do you like that name? Noa.
I think it's beautiful.
It means "long life." Spelled with an H.
But it's prettier without it.
In Noah's Ark, that's a story,
they survived and got to land.
There are animals in it.
I'll read it to you some day.
This is Uma.
You wanna know about her, don't you?
Well, you know,
you have the same eyes as she did.
Exactly.
And when she was a baby,
the shape of her face was just like yours.
She wanted to be an airplane pilot.
She liked to say "airplane pilot."
You would've had fun with her.
What happened is that when...
...when the regime took over,
we were forced to lock ourselves
inside the house.
And your daddy would go out
to get us food.
At first, it was fine,
but as time went on...
Uma wanted to go outside because...
because a girl can't stand
being locked up for too long
in her house, you know.
There wasn't enough room to play,
so one day,
she kept begging me
and insisting we go out.
And, um,
I said, "Okay."
We were only outside five minutes,
but they took her.
It was all my fault.
I should've known better.
I messed up.
What's wrong?
What's wrong? Are you okay?
You're freezing.
There we are.
You're snug as a bug in a rug like that.
My beanie looks cute on you.
You'll feel much better tomorrow, okay?
You're all bundled up.
Warm and cozy.
Sweet pea. All right. I got you.
DAY 12
No, no, no.
MAXIMUM
Nico! Nico!
Oh, come on, come on, connect.
Please, come on.
Please work. Come on, connect. Connect.
Nico. Nico.
- Mia.
- Can you hear me?
- Uh, yes, at last.
- It's finally you, my love.
I'm so sorry I couldn't call you.
I didn't have a signal.
And my cell is broken.
No, no, I mean the screen is broken.
Where are you?
- Listen to me, please, my love.
- What's wrong, Nico?
I won't be able to come for you.
You'll have to make it on your own.
Promise me you will.
Promise.
Nico, what's wrong?
Please, Nico. I'm scared. What's wrong?
My love, tell me.
- Nico...
- I'm... I'm hiding in a container.
I snuck onto a ship, but they found me.
And when I ran, they shot me.
Are you hurt?
I'm losing so much blood.
- What?
- My love...
- Honey?
- I just... I just wanted to say goodbye.
And I want you to know that I fought hard.
I fought hard. As hard as I could.
I promise I did.
And... you were right.
You were always right.
I'm too optimistic.
We should've stayed.
- No. No. Nico, listen to me.
- I'm sorry.
- Listen to me, Nico.
- So sorry.
Please, my love, listen to me.
- You saved our lives.
- How?
- Understand?
- How? You said "our lives"?
Yes, my love, she's here.
She's here, Nico. She was born.
She's a beautiful little girl.
- That's amazing.
- Yeah.
A girl, huh? See, I knew it.
Are you okay?
- Yeah. We're both fine. We're both fine.
- I wish I were with you.
You're here, Nico.
You are. You've been here the whole time.
You were here during my labor,
you were here
when I finally opened the container.
I promised I wouldn't give up
and I fought.
I fought so hard.
And you're here when I sing to her.
You're always here with me.
- What? You, sing?
- Yes.
Sweetheart,
what does she look like?
She looks like you.
She's so beautiful,
she's strong, and funny.
She makes me laugh,
she's caring just like you.
You know what? She's right here.
I'll put the phone next to her
so she can hear your voice.
- Okay.
- Sweet pea,
your daddy wants to talk to you.
He's on the phone. Say something.
Hello, how's my princess? I'm your daddy.
I'm the pesky guy
who pushed your foot all the time
when you were in your mommy's tummy.
Okay. Now listen.
I'm gonna tell you a secret.
If you ever feel sad
and confused about life,
close your eyes
and sit in your mom's lap for a while.
You'll see that when you're in her arms,
everything's all right. Always.
Did you hear her? She's brilliant.
Her name is Noa.
Noa?
Are you sure?
She looks like a Noa.
So as it turns out,
Noa was the perfect name for her.
Nico.
Yeah?
Nico, I love you more than yesterday.
But less than tomorrow.
DAY 18
DAY 15
DAY 20
DAY 23
MAXIMUM
DAY 26
DAY 14
I'M SICK OF EATING FISH
DAY 20
SHE'S BEEN SLEEPING ALL DAY
DAY 24
I CAN'T STOP THE WATER
I HAVE TO LIVE UP TOP
It's okay. I gotcha.
Hey!
Noa!
That was a seagull.
You know what that means, honey?
MAXIMUM
Okay.
Huh?
No!
No.
You're fucking kidding.
What's happening?
No!
Noa!
No. Go away!
Noa. Noa!
Noa!
Noa! Noa! Noa!
Noa, I'm coming!
Noa!
I'm here. Don't worry.
I'm here. Noa. Noa.
Everything's fine.
Hm...
We're almost there.
We've almost made it. Don't give up now.
Just gotta keep going
for a while longer.
Gotta hold on.
We've gotta live to tell our story, Noa.
Yeah, I know. They'll think we're crazy.
But we know it's true, don't we?
We put up a good fight, honey.
We did everything we could, didn't we?
My love, you saved me.
You saved my life.
Forgive me.
I was so scared.
But you gave me strength.
And I did everything I could...
didn't I?
I did everything I could.
I couldn't have done more.
- There's no fish, Dad!
- Wanna try this?
Do you wanna say something?
No, no. I'm only joking.
No, we only use the radio...
I told you.
I think you have to move.
Do you see those seagulls?
Can we go a little bit closer?
What's that?
Jesus Christ.
Hey.
Where's his family?
Come on!
You can do it! Harder!
That's it.
That's it. Turn her over.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
Get her over.
- Come on. Sit her up against there.
- Gently. There you go.
- Okay. Just get her over here.
- Hey.
You're okay. You're okay.
My daughter? My daughter.
- She's here, she's here.
- My daughter.
Mayday, mayday. We have an emergency here.
We pulled a woman
and a child out of the water.
The woman's okay.
She has...
We've given her CPR and she's alive.
She's okay. She's not hurt.
Hey. She's okay.
Yeah, yeah.
We're on our way back now.
We should be back in port
in about 20 minutes.
Your jacket's soaking wet.
Need to take it off.
No, no. Please don't. I want it on.
- Please. Please.
- It's okay. It's okay.
Are you hurt?
Do you have other children?
Were there others with you?
You're okay, you're safe. Okay?
Subtitle translation by Winifred Donlon
Modify by Blue-Bird™